



#### **Contacts:**

me@gauz.net

https://github.com/MrGauz

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/gauz

#### Languages:

English – advanced

German – advanced

Russian – native

Python – proficient PHP – proficient

C# - intermediate

I'm a Software Engineer with DevOps skills. Most of my experience is in web development, although I have worked on desktop and mobile apps as well. I love learning new things and passing on what I already know.

Python · PHP · C# / .NET · MySQL · PostgreSQL · MongoDB · Firebase · Redis AWS · GCP · CI/CD · Infrastructure as Code · Docker · Business Automation

# Experience

• Kodex AI, Senior Software Engineer

Berlin, Germany | Oct 2023 - Present

• I was a developer at an early-stage startup where I took backend projects from early prototypes to mature, stable systems. I set up monitoring, analytics, and various technical processes. I worked closely with the ML team to productionise AI research and serve models through well-documented APIs. I was also responsible for managing infrastructure across multiple clouds and providers. As the company grew, I led technical projects, mentored junior developers, and conducted workshops to help the team grow.

### • sendmoments GmbH, Software Engineer

Munich, Germany | Jul 2017 - Oct 2023

- I was part of a team that built a Web-to-Print e-commerce platform. I
  designed a real-time fraud-detection system, built logistics software to
  streamline print-shop workflows, and automated business processes such as
  employee onboarding and IT asset management. During the rollout of a
  corporate password manager, I ran IT-security masterclasses for staff.
- I managed Unix and Windows servers and our AWS estate. I implemented Infrastructure as Code with Puppet, maintained CI/CD pipelines, and automated end-to-end TLS certificate issuance and distribution across the stack.

#### • **Technical University of Munich,** Programming Tutor

Garching, Germany | Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

· I led Java tutorials for an introductory programming course, reviewed homework assignments, and graded final exams.

## Education

- Technical University of Munich, B.Sc. Information Systems 2018 - 2022
- · The program I studied is called "Economical Informatics" in German, and it taught me to translate business needs into technical solutions. Among other classes, I took courses in distributed systems, networks, cybersecurity, GDPR, accounting, and business administration.
- · In a Kotlin practical course, I created a Tinder-like app for picking a film for a movie night. Its code and written report are available on my GitHub.
- For my bachelor's project, I developed a website for IFAN a hate speech detection XAI model. The ML team needed a tool to make testing and development easier, as well as for the visualisation of the model to be showcased at conferences and to potential users.



# 🗃 Pet projects

· I love pet projects as a way to try out new technologies and automate my routines, whether it is watering plants on time or embedding metadata into podcasts. I enjoy coding Telegram bots the most because they can solve just about any problem from notifications about birthdays to organising a digitally-powered 8-hour quest through the city for a friend's birthday. You can see some of my projects on my GitHub.